hi dominica here from
easysowingforbeginners.com
in this tutorial today i'll be showing
you how to use these mini stapler sewing
machines
now this particular one i got from ebay
but
i've seen them on amazon and other
online places and they're all fairly
similar it's a mechanical one so you
operate it
just with your hand okay i'm going to
show you how to thread the machine up
first and then i'm going to
show you how to actually use it along
with some extra tips as well to
make sure that you're successful with
these because they can be a little bit
temperamental
okay so when you get your mini sewing
machine out of the box it will probably
already be threaded up for you
but just in case it's not i'm going to
show you how to do that first
so you have a little bobbin of thread
that should already be
on your machine you can actually remove
that if you want if you want to change
the color
or if you want to use a normal spool of
thread
you can use this longer spool pin here
and attach it onto your
machine like that okay or if you just
want to use a different color
with um on a bobbin you can
put the little spool pin through and
push it on like that
okay i'm gonna use this bright pink one
so it's easy for you guys to see
okay so to thread our little machine up
you need to pass your
thread tail here through your first
thread guide
okay and it needs to go from the bottom
and out through the top like that
okay your next thread guide is your
tension discs here so you'll find
there's two discs
that are held together with a spring
so you need to make sure your thread
goes in between
those two discs there we go
okay so your machine should look a
little something like this now
all right the next thread guide is
actually this little hook
here under the needle arm so
this is a bit of an awkward step so i
tend to get
my little pair of scissors and i just
use those
to get that thread up over the hook
see how many turns it takes there we go
got it
okay so you've got the first thread
guide here
second is through the tension discs and
the third one is
the hook there oh my little tension
knob is just falling off we'll just
screw that back on
okay the next thing you'll need to do is
thread the needle so it's important to
make sure that the needle is threaded
the correct way or else your machine
won't stitch at all so the thread needs
to be running
from behind the needle
and out through the front okay
and the best way to do this is to use
this little needle threader
so put the needle threader through the
eye of the needle
okay like that and i'm just going to
pass the thread through
okay let's pull that needle threader
through and the red tail should follow
it through the eye of the needle
okay and then the last step
what you need to do is make sure the
thread is going
under this fastening plate here so you
can actually lift the fastening plate
with a finger like so okay
so what i like to do is just lift it
right up without pushing the needle
bar down and then pull that
thread through like that
okay and now your machine should be
ready to sew okay so to start sewing
with your little machine
i tend to hold it in my right hand i
have the thread tail coming off to
the left here and the fabric will need
to come in from the right because the
fabric will move from the right
through to the left okay so to get the
fabric under
i'll just turn it this way so you can
see you can lift the
fastening plate up like so
and pop your fabric under
okay and then to stitch you'd simply
just push
all the way down until you hear a click
and then release it okay you just keep
repeating that
now when you get to the end of your
sewing an important tip
because this machine does a chain stitch
if you just take your stitching out and
pull the thread
it will unravel all of your stitching so
when you get to the end
pop your thumb and finger on the last
stitch
and then just do another stitch until it
releases from the hook underneath like
that
pull it through a little bit and then
snip it
like that okay
so i'll just show you quickly if you try
and leave it like that and
your thread pulls it will start
unraveling
okay now you don't want that so what you
need to do is turn your
sewing over and you'll see the last
little loop there
pull your thread through to the other
side by pulling that loop
and just by doing that that will secure
your stitching now to make it extra
secure if you grab your needle threader
from before
if you pass it under the last stitch
and put your thread tail through there
and then pull it through
and don't pull it all the way through
make sure you
have a little loop left over and you
want to
pass your thread tower through that
little loop
and pull it
and this should give your sewing some
extra strength to hold in there okay
so i'm just going to show you one more
thing so if you are doing
a hem of a pant or um
some other kind of sewing where you
don't want to where you can't sew off
the edge like that
i'll show you another option okay so so
i'm doing
a hem i've got my inside of the hem and
this will be the outside this is the
part that will be visible so you want
your straight stitch
on the outside of your clothing or
whatever you're stitching
you'd lift up that fastening plate i
want the whole thing to come up
lift up the fastening plate and put your
fabric in
so i'm just going to do a few stitches
just as a demonstration first
okay so so i've done my stitching and i
want to take the stapler off here
um i don't want to finish the the rest
off
what i'll do is grab those little
scissors and you just want to pull some
of that thread through
you can do it with your hand as well
just like that until you've got a couple
of inches or so
all right snip that thread
do one more stitch and then you can lift
up that fastening plate
and pull your stitching out
and then the same thing you just need to
pull from the loop at the back just to
secure your stitching
okay i hope you found this tutorial
useful
hit the thumbs up button leave a comment
down below
and don't forget to subscribe to keep up
with all my upcoming videos
if you're interested in seeing the
tutorials for
how to operate a handheld sewing machine
that's battery operated
then i recommend you check that one out
i also have a video for mini sewing
machines
and also these other portable mini
sewing machines
which are the ones i recommend for
beginning sellers who are on a budget
as you can find these on amazon for
around the 40 to
60 dollar mark in the us or you can find
them at spotlight when they're on
special for around 50 to 60 dollars
as well okay i will see you next time
[Music]
bye
you